MAINAK CHAKRABORTY

+1-240-408-9107 | mchakrab2@student.touro.edu | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

OBECTIVE: UI/UX Designer

I have a passion for finding opportunities that allow me to dive into the role of UI/UX design and to continue my learning journey in UX Design & Product Design. Collaborating with professionals and gaining hands on experience is something I am eagerly looking forward to. Currently I am actively searching for positions where I can contribute to groundbreaking projects, learn from mentors, and further enhance my skills while making an impact in the field of UX Design

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Software Skills: Microsoft Suite, Foundational HTML, CSS & JavaScript, Agile Methodology
- Designing Tools: Adobe Figma, Sketch, In Vision, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Balsamiq, Davinci Resolve
- · Community Service: At an NGO working towards education for underprivileged children in Mumbai.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Touro University – *Graduate Assistant*

New York City

Jun 2023 - Present

- · Conducted user interviews and surveys to understand student needs and preferences for website content.
- · Analyzed website traffic data to identify areas for improvement. Increased website user engagement by 12%
- · Managed and edited content for the university website, social media, ensuring consistent brand messaging and tone.
- Created and edited engaging workshops on current trends in higher education, attracting an average of 20 participants per session.
- Produced spotlight videos of instructors, students, and alumni, generating a 15% increase in video viewership on YouTube.
- Conducted in-depth user research, creating detailed journey maps that visualized user navigation patterns and pain points. Presented research findings and recommendations to the marketing team, influencing website design decisions and content
- creation.

Skills: Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Media Encoder, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop, Canva.

Ipsos Research – *Research Associate*

Mumbai, India

Jan 2022 - Jul 2022

- Marketing Strategy & Innovation
 - Performed professional market research with extensive experience in identifying target markets, analyzing customer behavior, industry trends, and competition for Mondelez.
 - Assisted senior researchers in questionnaire and survey design, conducting business forecasts, and participating in weekly team meetings with managers and leadership.
 - Performed seamless cross-functional coordination with field executives, data processing team and finance team, resulting in improving the material receipt success rate by 20% and increasing quality efficiency by 16%
 - Managed various vendors related to research work and materials, optimizing payment structures and ensuring high-quality research location and on-time in-home fieldwork.

Raptreels Productions – Digital Editor

Mumbai, India

Jul 2020 - Nov 2021

Commercial Video Editing & Client Support

- · Worked on commercial video editing for clients and provided technical support working one-on-one with in-house team members and freelancers to deliver high-quality content.
- Assisted various contributors to meet deadlines by introducing project matrix, resulting in time savings from 10 to 6 hours per project.
- Implemented seamless sound effects, voices, and music into videos for clients' social media platforms and assembled raw footage using Photoshop to create finalized products.

Bzinga (Zee Essel) – Product Intern

Mumbai, India

Apr 2020- Jun 2020

App Development & Digital Marketing

- · Managed social media profiles, created monthly content decks with copies and visuals, and analyzed daily reports to share MAU/DAU and YTD user data with UX team for continuous enhancement.
- Installed Bzinga App on Android/iOS and helped bring down the average cost per install (CPI) from \$0.40 to \$0.25

RGBA Studios – *Production Coordinator*

Mumbai, India

Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

VFX & Motion Graphics

- Conveyed client requirements, managed production schedules, coordinated manuscript flow, and assembled footage for efficient
- Effectively provided feedback to process managers and coordinated with Ad agencies and production houses.

EDUCATION

Masters in Web and Multimedia Design **Touro University, New York City**

Graduate School of Technology

Expected grad Aug 2024

Bachelor of Mass Media

University of Mumbai, India

MMK College of Commerce & Economics

August 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

· Marketing in Digital World

GIES School of Business GIES School of Business Jan 2021

· Digital Media and Marketing Principle Foundation Of User Experience (UX)

Jan 2021 Sep 2021

by Google